A Guide to the J. Rives Childs Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
J. Rives Childs Papers 1973-1976
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9256-i
This collection consists of ca. 700 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of the honorable J. Rivers Childs of Richmond in April 1978.
Biographical/Historical Information
J. Rives Childs was a diplomat, writer and former ambassador to Saudi Arabia, Yemen, and Ethiopia.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the papers of J. Rives Childs consists chiefly of personal correspondence dating from 1973-1976. This correspondence includes letters to congressmen and editors, and materials concerning the publication of his books and articles. Letters detailing his continuing ties with Randolph-Macon College and information regarding his trip to the Soviet Union in 1975 are also included.
Arrangement
These papers are divided into three sections: correspondence, printed material, and miscellaneous and retain their chronological arrangement.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence of J. Rives Childs 1973 Apr - 1976 Dec & n.d., 594 ALS and TLS
    9 folders
- Printed Material
  - Papers re Russian Tour of J. Rives Childs ca. 1974-1976
  - Programs and Invitations ca. 1974-1976
  - Newspaper Clippings ca. 1974-1976
  - Miscellaneous printed material ca. 1974-1976
- Miscellaneous
  - Genealogical material re J. Rives Childs ca. 1974-1976
  - Bills and reciepts re J. Rives Childs ca. 1974-1976
  - Miscellaneous material re J. Rives Childs ca. 1974-1976